

CONTACT INFO

■ Phan.Noi@lmu.de

4 +49 (0) 89/2180 - 6748

ResearchGate

Github

Homepage

For more information, please contact me via E-mail.

SKILLS

Experienced in Geostatistical analysis, Machine Learning, and Classification Algorithms.

Full experience with GIS software (Envi, ArcGIS).

Skilled in R, Python, Google Earth Engine (GEE)

THANH-NOI PHAN

Postdoctoral Researcher | Ludwig-Maximilians University of Munich

My broad research interests lie in understanding the interactions between human activities and surface climate, environment, and landscapes across various scales. I leverage fieldbased inventory data, advanced remote sensing techniques, data harmonization, and diverse geocomputational approaches to achieve my research objectives.

EDUCATION

University of Göttingen 11.2018

PhD in Geography (magna cum laude)

Göttingen, Germany

Dissertation: Air surface temperature estimation using MODIS land surface temperature data in northwest Vietnam

Asian Institute of Technology 6.2012

MSc in Natural Resources Management

Bangkok, Thailand

Thesis: Detecting Land Use and Land Cover Change using Remote Sensing and GIS: Case Study of Tam Nong District, Phu Tho Province, Vietnam

Hanoi University of Mining and Geology 6.2007

BSc in Geodesy (Survey Engineering)

Hanoi, Vietnam

Thesis: GPS Positioning

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher 06.2019

Ludwig-Maximilians University of Munich (LMU)

Munich, Germany

Associate Researcher 11.2018

University of Göttingen 05.2019

present

10.2013

Göttingen, Germany

Lecturer and researcher 03.2008

Vietnam National University of Agriculture (VNUA) 10.2013

Hanoi, Vietnam

Geodesy Engineer, Land/GPS Surveyor 07.2007

Geodetic and Topographic Division 02.2008

Hanoi, Vietnam

♣☐ TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Geodesy for Land Management Program 03.2008

Teaching Geodesy courses (Basic & Advanced) for Land Management Program at VNUA.

Hanoi, Vietnam

Photogrametry, Remote Sensing, and GIS 03.2008

Teaching Photogrametry, Remote Sensing, and GIS courses for Land Management 10.2013

Program at VNUA.

Hanoi, Vietnam

Introduction to Google Earth Engine for Big Data Analysis 10.2024

> This extracurricular course is designed to provide Bachelor's, Master's, and PhD students at LMU with the essential resources to start using Google Earth Engine (GEE).

> > Munich, Germany



11.2017 - 04.2018	Family Oriented Finishing Grant This grant offers stipends for PhD students who have families and demonstrate strong research results. ◆ Göttingen, Germany
11.2013 - 10.2017	Scholarship for PhD program at the University of Göttingen, Germany. Scholarship from the Government of Vietnam Göttingen, Germany
08.2010 - 06.2012	Scholarship from Ford Foundation Scholarship for Master Degree at Asian Institute of Technology (AIT), Bangkok, Thailand. ▼ Bangkok, Thailand
05.2005	Scholarship for outstanding student This scholarship, provided by The Aerial Photo - Topography Company and the Military Map Department of Vietnam, is awarded to the top 5 students at Hanoi University of Mining and Geology. P Hanoi, Vietnam

Scholarship for excellent students

The Hanoi University of Mining and Geology awards scholarships to excellent students during the academic year. Hanoi, Vietnam 09.2002 - 07.2007

Research Projects

MORE STEP - Mobility at risk: Sustaining the Mongolian Steppe Ecosystem | Website

This is a collaborative and interdisciplinary research project of Mongolian and German partners funded by the German Federal Ministry of Education and Research.

List of Publications

Google Scholar | Scopus | ResearchGate

Peer-Reviewed Journals (published)

[14]. Diem, P. K., Nguyen, C. T., Diem, N. K., Diep, N. T. H., Thao, P. T. B., Hong, T. G., & Phan, T.-N. (2024). Remote sensing for urban heat island research: Progress, current issues, and perspectives. Remote Sensing Applications: Society and Environment, 33. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsase.2023.101081

- [13]. Ji, S., Dashpurev, B., Phan, T.-N., Dorj, M., Jäschke, Y., & Lehnert, L. (2024). Above-ground biomass retrieval with multi-source data: Prediction and applicability analysis in Eastern Mongolia. Land Degradation & Development. https://doi.org/10.1002/ldr.5109
- [12]. Dashpurev, B., Dorj, M., Phan, T.-N., Bendix, J., & Lehnert, L. W. (2023). Estimating fractional vegetation cover and aboveground biomass for land degradation assessment in eastern Mongolia steppe: combining ground vegetation data and remote sensing. International Journal of Remote Sensing, 44(2), 452-468. https://doi.org/10 .1080/01431161.2023.2165421
- [11]. Nguyen, C. T., Kaewthongrach, R., Channumsin, S., Chongcheawchamnan, M., Phan, T.-N., & Niammuad, D. (2023). A regional assessment of ecological environment quality in Thailand special economic zone: Spatial heterogeneous influences and future prediction. Land Degradation & Development, 34(18), 5770-5787. https://doi .org/10.1002/ldr.4876
- [10]. Phan, T.-N., Dashpurev, B., Wiemer, F., & Lehnert, L. W. (2022). A simple, fast, and accurate method for land cover mapping in Mongolia. Geocarto International, 37(26), 14432-14450. https://doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2022 .2087759
- [9]. Dashpurev, B., Wesche, K., Jäschke, Y., Oyundelger, K., Phan, T.-N., Bendix, J., & Lehnert, L. W. (2021). A cost-effective method to monitor vegetation changes in steppes ecosystems: A case study on remote sensing of fire

- and infrastructure effects in eastern Mongolia. *Ecological Indicators*, 132. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2021 .108331
- [8]. **Phan, T.-N**., Kuch, V., & Lehnert, L. W. (2020). Land Cover Classification using Google Earth Engine and Random Forest Classifier—The Role of Image Composition. *Remote Sensing*, 12(15). https://doi.org/10.3390/rs12152411 (Highly Cited Paper)
- [7]. Bayat, M., **Phan, T.-N**., Zare, R., & Bui, D. (2019). A Semi-empirical Approach Based on Genetic Programming for the Study of Biophysical Controls on Diameter-Growth of Fagus orientalis in Northern Iran. *Remote Sensing*, 11(14). https://doi.org/10.3390/rs11141680
- [6]. **Phan, T.-N.**, Kappas, M., Nguyen, K. T., Tran, T. P., Tran, Q. V., & Emam, A. R. (2019). Evaluation of MODIS land surface temperature products for daily air surface temperature estimation in northwest Vietnam. *International Journal of Remote Sensing*, 40(14), 5544-5562. https://doi.org/10.1080/01431161.2019.1580789
- [5]. **Phan, T.-N**., & Kappas, M. (2018). Application of MODIS land surface temperature data: a systematic literature review and analysis. *Journal of Applied Remote Sensing*, 12(04). https://doi.org/10.1117/1.Jrs.12.041501
- [4]. **Phan, T.-N**., Kappas, M., & Tran, T. (2018). Land Surface Temperature Variation Due to Changes in Elevation in Northwest Vietnam. *Climate*, 6(2). https://doi.org/10.3390/cli6020028
- [3]. **Phan, T.-N.**, & Kappas, M. (2018). *Comparison of Random Forest, k-Nearest Neighbor, and Support Vector Machine Classifiers for Land Cover Classification Using Sentinel-2 Imagery. Sensors (Basel)*, 18(1). doi:10.3390/s18010018 (Highly Cited Paper)
- [2]. **Phan, T.-N**., Degener, J., & Kappas, M. (2017). Comparison of Multiple Linear Regression, Cubist Regression, and Random Forest Algorithms to Estimate Daily Air Surface Temperature from Dynamic Combinations of MODIS LST Data. *Remote Sensing*, 9(5). https://doi.org/10.3390/rs9050398
- [1]. **Phan, T.-N.**, Kappas, M., & Degener, J. (2016). Estimating Daily Maximum and Minimum Land Air Surface Temperature Using MODIS Land Surface Temperature Data and Ground Truth Data in Northern Vietnam. *Remote Sensing*, 8(12). https://doi.org/10.3390/rs8121002

Peer-Reviewed Journals (Submitted, Under Review)

- [4]. Oyundelger, K., Jäschke, Y., Gonchigsumlaa, G., Batjav, B., Damdindorj, S., Munkhzul, O., **Phan, T.-N.**, Mehring, M., Drees, L., Kasymov, U., Ring, I., Ritz, C.M., Wesche, K. (2024). Assessing pasture quality in Mongolian steppe: cross-validating local traditional knowledge and standard ecological surveys (Submitted).
- [3]. Ji, S., Gonchigsumlaa, G., Damdindorj, S., Tseren, T., Sharavjamts, D., Otgondemberel, A., Gurjav, E., Puntsagsuren, M., Tsabatshir, B., Gungaa, T., Batbold, N., Drees, L., Ganbayar, B., Orosoo, D., Lkhamsuren, B., Ganbat, B., Damdinsuren, M., Gombosuren, G., Dashpurev, B., **Phan, T.-N**., Dejid, N., Müller, T., Lehnert, L. (2024). Monitoring breakpoints under grazing pressure in Eastern Mongolia (Under Review).
- [2]. Nguyen, C. T., Diem, P. K., Dang, H.N., Diem, N. K., Diep, N. T. H., **Phan, T.-N.**, Vo, Q.M. (2024). Leveraging Convolutional Neural Networks and Textural Features for Tropical Fruit Tree Species Classification. (Under Review).
- [1]. Wang, Y., Oyunbileg, M., Khaliun, U., Batlai, O., **Phan, T.-N.**, Lehnert, L., Gonchigsumlaa, G., Damdindorj, S., Kasymov, U., Drees, L., Mehring, M., Dejid, N., Wesche, K. (2024). Herder mobility matters yet climate controls plant community composition in eastern Mongolian steppe. (Under Review).

Conference Publications

[5]. **Phan, T.-N.**, Zerres, V., Svanidze, D., Dashpurev, B., and L. W. Lehnert (2024). Grassland fire monitoring and their effects on ecosystems in Mongolian steppes. AGU24, 9-13 Dec, Washington D.C.

- [4]. Dashpurev, B., **Phan, T.-N.**, J. Bendix, L. Lehnert (2022). Deriving vegetation cover and land degradation in the vast eastern Mongolian Steppe from Sentinel 2 using random forest. ESA Living Planet Symposium, Bonn.
- [3]. Dashpurev, B., **Phan, T.-N**., J. Bendix, and L. W. Lehnert (2021). Estimating the Effect of Infrastructure on Vegetation Degradation in Eastern Mongolia Steppe Using Machine Learning and Remote Sensing. IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium IGARSS.
- [2]. Lehnert, L. W. & **Phan, T.-N**. (2020). Comparison of fire products in Mongolia reveals contrasting results. 22nd EGU General Assembly, Vol. 22, p. 11064.
- [1]. **Phan, T.-N.**, Y. Jäschke, O. Chuluunkhuyag, M. Oyunbileg, K. Wesche, and L. W. Lehnert (2020). Remote sensing of grassland communities in Mongolian Steppe combining multi-source data and machine learning classification algorithms. 22nd EGU General Assembly, Vol. 22, p. 13399.

Reviewr Activities

Elsevier (Sustainable Cities and Society; ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing; Flora; Advances in Space Research; International Journal of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation);

MDPI (Remote Sensing);

Nature (Scientific Reports);

IEEE (IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters);

Taylor & Francis (Physical Geography; Geocarto International; International Journal of Digital Earth);

Wiley (Earth and Space Science; Ecology and Evolution; Land Degradation & Development);

Springer (Environmental Earth Sciences; Environmental Monitoring and Assessment; SN Applied Sciences; Natural Hazards)

References

Prof. Dr. Lukas Lehnert

Postdoctoral Mentor
Department of Geography
Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München

Phone: +49 89 2180 6681 Email: lehnert.lu@lmu.de

Prof. Dr. Martin Kappas

PhD Advisor

Department of Cartography, GIS & Remote Sensing

Georg-August-Universität Göttingen

Phone: +49 551 39 8071 Email: mkappas@gwdg.de

Assoc. Prof. Dr. Nguyen Thi Hong Diep

Collaborator in Vietnam
College of Environment and Natural Resources
Can Tho University, Vietnam

Email: nthdiep@ctu.edu.vn

Prof. Dr. Karsten Wesche

Collaborator in the MoreStep Project
Director, Senckenberg Museum of Natural History
Head of Section Phanerogams

Phone: +49 3581 476053-00

Email: karsten.wesche@senckenberg.de